<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link>https://danstroot.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:25:35 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://danstroot.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Man Least Likely to Succeed in Politics</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2017/03/19/the-man-least-likely-to-succeed-in-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:25:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2017/03/19/the-man-least-likely-to-succeed-in-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/Elvis-Nixon.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nixon meets Elvis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dick Nixon understood that getting the smart, popular kids to vote for you didn&amp;rsquo;t matter. He called the popular kids &amp;ldquo;Franklins&amp;rdquo; and he called his kind the &amp;ldquo;Orthogonians&amp;rdquo;.  Nixon discovered that being hated by the &amp;ldquo;Franklins&amp;rdquo; was no impediment to political success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklins were well-rounded, graceful, moved smoothly, talked slickly. Nixon’s new club, the Orthogonians, was for the strivers, those not to the manner born, the commuter students like him. He persuaded his fellows that reveling in one’s unpolish was a nobility of its own&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Orthogonians’ base was among Whittier’s athletes. On the surface, jocks seem natural Franklins, the Big Men on Campus. But Nixon always had a gift for looking under social surfaces to see and exploit the subterranean truths that roiled underneath. It was an eminently Nixonian insight: that on every sports team there are only a couple of stars, and that if you want to win the loyalty of the team for yourself, the surest, if least glamorous, strategy is to concentrate on the nonspectacular—silent—majority. The ones who labor quietly, sometimes resentfully, in the quarterback’s shadow: the linemen, the guards, the punter. Nixon himself was exemplarily nonspectacular: the 150-pounder was the team’s tackle dummy, kept on squad by a loving, tough, and fatherly coach who appreciated Nixon’s unceasing grit&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nixon beat a Franklin for student body president. Looking back later, acquaintances marveled at the feat of this awkward, skinny kid the yearbook called “a rather quiet chap about campus,” dour and brooding, who couldn’t even win a girlfriend, who attracted enemies, who seemed, a schoolmate recalled, “the man least likely to succeed in politics.” They hadn’t learned what Nixon was learning. Being hated by the right people was no impediment to political success. The unpolished, after all, were everywhere&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; Rick Perlstein: &amp;ldquo;Nixonland: The Rise of a President and the Fracturing of America&amp;rdquo;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-unpolished-after-all-are-everywhere&#34;&gt;The unpolished, after all, are everywhere.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump reached out to those who are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less political&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less educated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less suspicious of patently false claims &lt;em&gt;(Mexico will pay for the wall!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less willing to do their research and homework &lt;em&gt;(You mean my healthcare is Obama care?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less tolerant of people of different races&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less tolerant of people of different religions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less tolerant of female leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less tolerant of &amp;ldquo;tree huggers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-reach-these-people&#34;&gt;How do you reach these people?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They no longer read the LA Times, the New York Times, or the Washington Post (many probably never did).  They no longer watch the evening news with Dan Rather.  Rather, they glance up from Snapchat to see who got the rose on The Bachelor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media is how you reach these people. One consistent theme across both the Trump victory and the Brexit success was their use of advanced marketing techniques. These campaigns utilized the power of emotion to drive their narratives and leveraged the complexities of Big Data to &lt;strong&gt;direct those messages at segmented groups via social media with devastating effect.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One connection between the Trump campaign and the Brexit campaign was the alleged involvement of communications firm Cambridge Analytica (CA) – of which allegedly Steve Bannon was formerly chairman of the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cambridge Analytica uses psychometric profiling to identify potential voters and to inform their approach and rhetoric in reaching them. Psychometrics allows the utilization big data to assess vast numbers of people and construct personality profiles on each person in order to pinpoint individuals most likely to convert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cambridge Analytica claims to have &lt;strong&gt;up to 5,000 data points per person&lt;/strong&gt; – and they’re talking about almost every person in the United States, plus many more worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-build-a-profile-of-a-person&#34;&gt;How do you build a profile of a person?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, by studying a person&amp;rsquo;s Facebook &amp;ldquo;likes&amp;rdquo; researchers can know them better than their spouse. Michael Kosinski, when researching at Cambridge University, created an experiment where he posted a free-to-access psychometric test online to gather small amounts of data to inform his data analysis. This test went viral on Facebook and Kosinski was able to draw some powerful conclusions from his study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Kosinski continued to work on the models incessantly: before long, he was able to evaluate a person better than the average work colleague, merely on the basis of ten Facebook “likes.” &lt;strong&gt;Seventy “likes” were enough to outdo what a person’s friends knew, 150 what their parents knew, and 300 “likes” what their partner knew.&lt;/strong&gt; More “likes” could even surpass what a person thought they knew about themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 170 likes per person, Kosinski’s methods were able to predict the following attributes with the connected rates of accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/Facebook-research.png&#34; alt=&#34;Kosinski Research&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-this-information-be-used-to-influence-voters&#34;&gt;Can this information be used to influence voters?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One psychometric framework is known as The Big Five, or OCEAN.  This approach is centered around summarizing an individual’s personality through relation to five key categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/ocean.png&#34; alt=&#34;OCEAN&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know this methodology is employed by Cambridge Analytica as their CEO Alexander Nix is pictured here below giving a presentation with the Big Five methodology taking center stage as one of the ways of understanding data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/Nix-presenting-research.png&#34; alt=&#34;Alexander Nix&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A politician in a US election needs to appeal to more than 65 million people in order to win the election. You need to find people susceptible to your product or message and be able to convert them. This is where the psychometric emotional mapping techniques offered through the Big Five methodology can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-need-for-cognition-scale&#34;&gt;The Need for Cognition Scale&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another method to target voters is called the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psy.ohio-state.edu/petty/documents/ncogscale.pdf&#34;&gt;Need for Cognition Scale&lt;/a&gt;.  This method is used in psychometrics to measure “the extent to which individuals are inclined towards effortful cognitive activities”, or feel “a need to understand and make reasonable the experiential world”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scale is used to understand how big an impact emotions make upon an individual’s decision-making process. Persons &lt;strong&gt;low&lt;/strong&gt; on the Need for Cognition Scale &lt;strong&gt;tend to form their opinions based heavily on emotion.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research finds that Trump has attracted a disproportionate (and unprecedented) number of “low-information voters” to his campaign. Furthermore, these voters are more likely to respond to emotional appeals — whether about the economy, immigration, Muslims, racial relations, sexism, and even hostility to the first African American U.S. president, Barack Obama. They are the ideal constituency for a candidate like Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We define low-information voters as those who do not know certain basic facts about government and lack what psychologists call a “need for cognition.” Those with a high need for cognition have a positive attitude toward tasks that require reasoning and effortful thinking and are, therefore, more likely to invest the time and resources to do so when evaluating complex issues. Those with a low need for cognition, on the other hand, find little reward in the collection and evaluation of new information when it comes to problem solving and the consideration of competing issue positions. They are more likely to rely on cognitive shortcuts, such as “experts” or other opinion leaders, for cues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bqfoot&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; Richard Fording and Sanford Schram: &amp;ldquo;‘Low information voters’ are a crucial part of Trump’s support&amp;rdquo;, Washington Post, November 7, 2016&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voters who score poorly on the Need for Cognition Scale &lt;strong&gt;are easier targets to sell political ideas to.&lt;/strong&gt; They are the easiest group of floating voters to target and capture based on a emotional message, delivered or shared by somebody they trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-social-media-be-weaponized-to-exploit-targeted-voters&#34;&gt;Can Social Media be &amp;ldquo;weaponized&amp;rdquo; to exploit targeted voters?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know there are millions of fake accounts and highly active bots on all the social media platforms. Since these companies are valued by the number of accounts they have, or the number of accounts acquired, or &amp;ldquo;active users&amp;rdquo;, they have little incentive to block the creation of fake accounts and activity bots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italian security researchers Andrea Stroppa and Carlo De Micheli, in a report released four years ago, in 2013, claimed that they found 20 million fake accounts for sale on Twitter. Jason Ding, a research scientist at Barracuda Labs, told NBC News that the number of Twitter accounts that were fake was &amp;ldquo;at least 10 percent, maybe more.&amp;rdquo; Twitter, according to The Wall Street Journal, claimed in its Securities and Exchange Commission report that only 5 percent of its accounts were fake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people who run the fake accounts and the bot farms where you can buy followers on Twitter, or likes on Facebook, are no longer selling fake persona, they are now &lt;strong&gt;selling political influence&lt;/strong&gt;. Why buy just buy fake followers on twitter when you can tweet some fake news and have thousands of retweets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bots can also be used to silence people with opposing views.  An automated army of pro-Donald J. Trump chatbots overwhelmed similar programs supporting Hillary Clinton five to one in the days leading up to the presidential election, according to a report published Thursday by researchers at Oxford University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bots targeted people by a hashtag symbol, like #Clinton. Their purpose: to rant, confuse people on facts, or simply muddy discussions, said Philip N. Howard, a sociologist at the Oxford Internet Institute and one of the authors of the report. In some cases, the bots would post embarrassing photos, make references to the Federal Bureau of Investigation inquiry into Mrs. Clinton’s private email server, or produce false statements, for instance, that Mrs. Clinton was about to go to jail or was already in jail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;closing-the-deal&#34;&gt;Closing the Deal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a voter has been &amp;ldquo;sold&amp;rdquo;, or converted, then “confirmation bias&amp;rdquo; takes over. Confirmation bias is the tendency people have to embrace information that supports their beliefs and reject information that contradicts them. Of the many forms of faulty thinking that have been identified, confirmation bias is among the best catalogued; it’s the subject of entire textbooks’ worth of experiments. If reason is designed to generate sound judgments, then it’s hard to conceive of a more serious design flaw than confirmation bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, people are not randomly wrong. Presented with someone else’s argument, we’re usually quite adept at spotting the weaknesses. Almost invariably, the positions we’re blind about are our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-38724082&#34;&gt;BBC: Massive networks of fake accounts found on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nbcnews.com/business/1-10-twitter-accounts-fake-say-researchers-2D11655362&#34;&gt;NBC: 1 in 10 Twitter accounts is fake, say researchers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.process.st/science-of-persuasion/&#34;&gt;What Marketers Can Learn from Trump About The Science of Persuasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/937590/for-casual-us-readers-the-person-who-shares-a-story-on-social-media-counts-for-more-than-the-actual-news-source/&#34;&gt;Who shares the story, not who reports the news, is what counts for casual readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://politicalbots.org/&#34;&gt;politicalbots.org: Project on Algorithms, Computational Propaganda, and Digital Politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/18/technology/automated-pro-trump-bots-overwhelmed-pro-clinton-messages-researchers-say.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;NYTimes: Automated Pro-Trump Bots Overwhelmed Pro-Clinton Messages, Researchers Say&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2016/11/17/how-pro-trump-twitter-bots-spread-fake-news.html&#34;&gt;The Daily Beast: How Pro-Trump Twitter Bots Spread Fake News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/19/facebook-will-never-take-responsibility-for-fake-news/&#34;&gt;techcrunch: Facebook continues to be under fire for peddling fake news, but the platform will never take real responsibility.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/02/27/why-facts-dont-change-our-minds&#34;&gt;The New Yorker: Why Facts Don&amp;rsquo;t Change our Minds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psy.ohio-state.edu/petty/documents/ncogscale.pdf&#34;&gt;Need for Cognition Scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://urban.hunter.cuny.edu/~schram/trumplowinformationvotersfinal.pdf&#34;&gt;The Cognitive and Emotional Sources of Trump Support: The Case of Low-Information Voters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2016/11/07/low-information-voters-are-a-crucial-part-of-trumps-support/&#34;&gt;The Washington Post: ‘Low information voters’ are a crucial part of Trump’s support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Feel the Need for Speed</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2017/01/10/i-feel-the-need-for-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 10:25:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2017/01/10/i-feel-the-need-for-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/speed.png&#34; alt=&#34;San Francisco MOMA&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today google released a &lt;a href=&#34;https://testmysite.withgoogle.com&#34;&gt;new tool&lt;/a&gt; to test how mobile friendly your website is.  Since I recently rebuilt this site and been using a variety of tools to test it I was excited to see how well the site scored.  The UI is very nice but you have to opt-in to email to get your detailed report. I am definitely not a fan of that &amp;ldquo;dark pattern&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually my go-to benchmark is the the venerable &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/&#34;&gt;Google PageSpeed Insights&lt;/a&gt;. PageSpeed Insights is very clear about delivering actionable steps you can take to improve overall speed and performance.  Not too long ago Google also added a mobile section to give you insight about your mobile page performance as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I recently adopted Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GoogleChrome/lighthouse&#34;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; tool and found that to be exceptionally useful, particularly since it is service worker aware.  As a result this site will now run even when the network connection is severed on your mobile device. (Service workers should be a separate article)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has pushed hard to support the unprecedented move to mobile device browsing. In November 2014, Google started labeling sites as “mobile-friendly” to denote which pages are optimized for phones. In February 2015, Google announced plans to roll out mobile ranking changes on April 21 (an unprecedented move — the company almost never announces algorithm changes in advance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently (May 2016) Google announced it is rolling out an update to mobile search results that “increases the effect” of its mobile-friendly ranking signal. The goal is to “help our users find even more pages that are relevant and mobile-friendly,&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is crystal clear that making your site mobile-friendly will help your rankings, but guess what?  Making your site mobile-friendly makes it a &lt;strong&gt;better experience for everyone, all the time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance benefits everyone. Don&amp;rsquo;t waste the time of visitors to your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsiveness benefits everyone.  I rarely if ever have the browser on my laptop at full screen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making your site handle network issues benefits everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words making your site run well on a phone means it will run great on more capable hardware with more reliable networking and your page ranking will reflect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://testmysite.withgoogle.com&#34;&gt;https://testmysite.withgoogle.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GoogleChrome/lighthouse&#34;&gt;https://github.com/GoogleChrome/lighthouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2016/03/16/google-will-start-ranking-mobile-friendly-sites-even-higher-in-may/&#34;&gt;http://venturebeat.com/2016/03/16/google-will-start-ranking-mobile-friendly-sites-even-higher-in-may/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/&#34;&gt;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you are in San Francisco go visit MOMA</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2016/11/16/if-you-are-in-san-francisco-go-visit-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 10:25:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2016/11/16/if-you-are-in-san-francisco-go-visit-moma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/sfmoma.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;San Francisco MOMA&#34; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;If you are in San Francisco go visit MOMA. Just go. Now.&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is No Such Thing as Not Voting</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2016/11/07/there-is-no-such-thing-as-not-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 15:15:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2016/11/07/there-is-no-such-thing-as-not-voting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/dfw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David Foster Wallace&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you are bored and disgusted by politics and don&amp;rsquo;t bother to vote, you are in effect voting for the entrenched establishments of the two major parties, who please rest assured are not dumb, and who are keenly aware that it is in their interests to keep you disgusted and bored and cynical and to give you every possible reason to stay at home doing one-hitters and watching MTV on primary day. By all means stay home if you want, but don&amp;rsquo;t bullshit yourself that you&amp;rsquo;re not voting. In reality, there is no such thing as not voting: you either vote by voting, or you vote by staying home and tacitly doubling the value of some diehard&amp;rsquo;s vote.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; David Foster Wallace&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free to Believe Anything</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2016/10/30/free-to-believe-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 19:50:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2016/10/30/free-to-believe-anything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/comic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cognitive Bias&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up, when you read the paper, watched the news, saw a film or a picture, you inherently believed in it.  You trusted the reality it portrayed. You trusted in journalism and even believed the news was actually &amp;ldquo;fair and balanced&amp;rdquo;. Then technology destroyed the business model of traditional journalism. The news institutions of the 20th century, print newspapers, the evening broadcast news, the trusted anchorman, are but relics of the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned to the Internet, but then we all learned the hard way that we can’t trust the Internet. We no longer know what is real and what is fake.  With everything now digital, and with excellent tools to edit audio, video, and photos, we have become skeptics. As soon as we see a viral video on YouTube we immediately say to ourselves “that’s fake”. Every magazine with a beautiful girl on the cover we think to ourselves “Photoshop”. When we read a blog post we think “spin”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is filled with anti-vaxxers, World Trade truthers, Kennedy theorists, religious fanatics of all stripes, and people who think that Barack Obama is a foreign-born Muslim. (He&amp;rsquo;s not). Since we no longer trust the news or what we read on the Internet we live in strange and interesting times. Now people are free to believe whatever they want to believe by discounting anything they see that does not align with their beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the new media landscape, the wall between news and entertainment is crumbling. The value of news is measured by its popularity. The loudest voice gets the most listeners. A lie bears equal weight as a fact.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; Vernon E. Jordan Jr., The Wall Street Journal&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big internet platforms, through their algorithms, have become an eye of a needle which news and media must pass through, limiting the content a person sees to that which &lt;strong&gt;already&lt;/strong&gt; conforms to their views. The Internet is becoming one big &amp;ldquo;echo chamber&amp;rdquo; which is designed to filter and shape the information someone sees based on previous searches, as well as information it might have about their location or preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“More likely than not, you get your news from Facebook, forty-four per cent of US adults get news on the site, and 61% of millennials … if that doesn’t frighten you, you don’t know enough about Facebook’s algorithm. If you have a parent who’s a Trump supporter, they are seeing a completely different set of news items than you are.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; Caleb Gardner, president Obama’s former social media adviser&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angela Merkel has joined a growing number of critics who have highlighted the dangers of receiving information that confirms an existing opinion or is recommended by people with similar ideas. Merkel called the issue a “challenge not just for political parties but for society as a whole”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Algorithms, when they are not transparent, can lead to a distortion of our perception, they can shrink our expanse of information.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; Angela Merkel, Chancellor of Germany&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Repeat a lie often enough and it becomes the truth”, is a law of propaganda often attributed to the Nazi Joseph Goebbels. Among psychologists this is known as the &amp;ldquo;illusion of truth&amp;rdquo; effect. Because we need to make quick judgements, we adopt mental shortcuts called heuristics. Relying on how often you&amp;rsquo;ve heard something to judge how truthful something feels is a heuristic strategy we all use. If we are only shown the news and information we choose to see, we are all reinforcing our own cognitive biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is our increasingly polarized country due going to get even worse because we are only fed the information we want to see, and conflicting information is filtered from view? Are the UK&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Brexit&amp;rdquo; movement and the USA&amp;rsquo;s Donald Trump just the beginning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump bypassed the old media gatekeepers and took his message straight to the electorate, using Twitter. Partisan websites and bloggers amplified his message. Mainstream television gave the candidate abundant free airtime, because his behavior was &amp;ldquo;entertaining&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, all candidates have equal access to technology, and of course we all have the freedom to listen to news and information the comfortably fits our views of the world. But isn&amp;rsquo;t a a healthy democracy dependent on people being confronted by opposing ideas?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/oct/27/angela-merkel-internet-search-engines-are-distorting-our-perception&#34;&gt;Angela Merkel: internet search engines are &amp;lsquo;distorting perception&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.journalism.org/2015/06/01/facebook-top-source-for-political-news-among-millennials/&#34;&gt;Facebook Top Source for Political News Among Millennials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20161026-how-liars-create-the-illusion-of-truth&#34;&gt;How liars create the &amp;lsquo;illusion of truth&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wsj.com/articles/both-old-and-new-media-are-failing-voters-1478216173&#34;&gt;Both Old and New Media Are Failing Voters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/03/technology/how-the-internet-is-loosening-our-grip-on-the-truth.html&#34;&gt;How the Internet Is Loosening Our Grip on the Truth&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 19:50:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;However you know me, or however you found me, I’m glad you are here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been a Chief Information Officer for a long time and it&amp;rsquo;s clear that “managing information” is just the price of entry. In today&amp;rsquo;s world I think CIO should mean “Chief Innovation Officer”. Managing innovation buys you a seat at the head table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ambition is to find ways in which technology and innovation can be leveraged for more effective, more engaging, and more sustainable business growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples I am interested are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harnessing the consumerization of technology for the enterprise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encouraging and managing data “curation” and ownership - a precursor to better analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to propagate ideas, mass collaboration and the social enterprise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social brand development, social capital and online reputation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frictionless security - i.e. security that will not be actively resisted by employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development approaches that are rapid, iterative &amp;amp; nimble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scale computing in all forms, shapes and sizes (Cloud, Software as a Service, Platform as a service, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-i-ve-worked&#34;&gt;Where I&amp;rsquo;ve Worked&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accenture.com/us-en/pages/index.aspx&#34;&gt;Associate Partner: Accenture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://us.allianzgi.com/Pages/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;Global CIO: Allianz Global Investors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-service&#34;&gt;Community Service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Board Member, Ronald McDonald House, Los Angeles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology Committee Member, Santa Margarita Catholic High School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of California at Los Angeles, BA Economics, 1985

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magna Cum Laude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phi Beta Kappa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-example-open-source-contributions&#34;&gt;Some Example Open Source Contributions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dstroot/skeleton&#34;&gt;Skeleton&lt;/a&gt; (maintainer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Boostrap&lt;/a&gt; (contributor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; (contributor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://helmetjs.github.io/&#34;&gt;Helmet&lt;/a&gt; (contributor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-little-more-on-me-the-personal-side&#34;&gt;A Little More on Me - the Personal Side&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been happily married to Julie for over twenty-five years, and have I have two children, Matt and Elise, who make me very proud. Julie and I met at UCLA. Go Bruins!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorites movies are Princess Bride and Dead Poets Society. I actually have &amp;ldquo;Carpe Diem&amp;rdquo; imprinted on my custom iPad cover!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love driving/riding anything with a motor and enjoy both dirt and street motorcycing and yes I probably go too fast. I generally love anything outdoors. Seems I have really gotten into hiking lately. I appreciate a good 10-15 mile summit hike and have hit most of the local southern California peaks. It&amp;rsquo;s good to get your heart rate up for 4-8 hours!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite place on earth is Hawaii, so a big mahalo to all of you who feel the same way. There is no place else where I can literally step off the plane and feel the weight lift from my shoulders and my spirit open up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-details-about-this-site&#34;&gt;Technical Details About This Site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are all standing on the back of giants and I am constantly amazed at the quality and diversity of the open source tools available now. I love learning and using new technology, and I am a curious person, so I am always interested in what technologies others use to create sites - so I thought I might share what tools I am using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is very simple. It is a static site built using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick list of what I am currently using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source code and content is managed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site analytics are provided by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/analytics/&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The build system is &lt;a href=&#34;http://gulpjs.com/&#34;&gt;Gulp.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CSS is compiled from &lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/&#34;&gt;SCSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site comments are provided by &lt;a href=&#34;http://disqus.com/&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!-- *   Site mailing list is managed via [Mailchimp](http://mailchimp.com/) --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Surface Studio is Mindblowing</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2016/10/29/microsoft-surface-studio-is-mindblowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:59:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2016/10/29/microsoft-surface-studio-is-mindblowing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/Surface_Studio.jpg&#34; srcset=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/Surface_Studio2x.jpg 2x&#34; alt=&#34;{{ .Site.Author.name }}&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saw the new Microsoft Surface Studio this weekend at the Microsoft store at the South Coast Plaza. I thought the display is pretty mind blowing. I have gotten used to wide screen displays but somehow the resolution and format of the screen just feels right. The display floats in space and fills your field of vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surface dial seems like it would be a gimmick but it isn&amp;rsquo;t. It feels very natural particularly when zooming in and out. Tilting the display down and working right on top of it is spectacular. Way to go Microsoft - you hit it out of the park!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proprietary Software is an Unsafe Building Material</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2015/10/03/proprietary-software-is-an-unsafe-building-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2015/10/03/proprietary-software-is-an-unsafe-building-material/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/volkswagen.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Volkswagen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point in time I worked for an organization that banned the use of open source software.  They were concerned that in the event of issues &amp;ldquo;there would be no support&amp;rdquo;.  At the time they believed that commercial software from companies like IBM, Oracle, Microsoft and SAP was &amp;ldquo;safer&amp;rdquo; because there was a commercial entity that stood behind the products they sold and provided support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;now-that-s-changing&#34;&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s changing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most technology leadership today recognizes that proprietary software is not safer than open source software. Basic metrics around the number of disclosed vulnerabilities and &amp;ldquo;time to patch availability&amp;rdquo; seem to give an edge to open source software at least being patched faster.  Not only that but you have the option to inspect the code yourself, and patch it yourself - options that are simply not available with commercial, closed software. This causes a re-evaluation of the relationship of proprietary, commercial software to operating a safe and secure business.

The recent Volkswagen scandal brings to light the broader question of how vulnerable we are to software that is beyond oversight.  Today when we have software running critical systems like medical devices, transportation systems, elevators, and cars we are realizing this code &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be open to inspection. This does not mean the code must be open source - only that the code must be available for inspection and oversight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is responsible for evaluating the risks of new devices and monitoring the safety and efficacy of those currently on market. The software on these devices performs life-sustaining functions such as cardiac pacing and defibrillation, drug delivery, and insulin administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the agency is unlikely to scrutinize the software operating on devices during any phase of the regulatory process unless a model that has already been surgically implanted repeatedly malfunctions or is recalled. Despite the crucial importance of these devices medical device software is considered the exclusive property of its manufacturers, meaning neither patients nor their doctors are permitted to access their source code or test its security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;proprietary-software-puts-us-at-risk&#34;&gt;Proprietary software puts us at risk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Columbia University professor, Eben Moglen, who founded the Software Freedom Law Center, has argued proprietary, and thus invisible, software puts us all at risk. He uses the analogy of being able to inspect an elevator&amp;rsquo;s operating mechanical condition as a foundational principle for having &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; elevators.  But isn&amp;rsquo;t the software that operates  elevators necessary to inspect as well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Proprietary software is an unsafe building material”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; Eben Moglen, Columbia University&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we have &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; cars or medical devices when the software is a black box and we simply have to trust the manufacturers? The code in automobiles is tightly protected under the Digital Millennium Copyright Act. Last year, several groups sought to have the code made available for “good-faith testing, identifying, disclosing and fixing of malfunctions, security flaws or vulnerabilities”. In response, a group of automobile manufacturers said that opening the code to scrutiny could create “serious threats to safety and security.” Think about that for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When proprietary code inflicts harm, such as Volkswagen’s polluting cars, the creators of that code must be held accountable. It’s definitely time to start demanding appropriate transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/23/nyregion/volkswagens-diesel-fraud-makes-critic-of-secret-code-a-prophet.html&#34;&gt;Volkswagen’s Diesel Fraud Makes Critic of Secret Code a Prophet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2015/09/volkswagen-open-iot/&#34;&gt;VW’s Cheating Proves We Must Open Up the Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it Secure?</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2015/09/26/is-it-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2015/09/26/is-it-secure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/SmartCarLock.png&#34; alt=&#34;Security&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q&lt;/em&gt;: Is it secure? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;: No it is not. Security is never binary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q&lt;/em&gt;: OK, how secure is it? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;: It seems like you just asked that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q&lt;/em&gt;: No, the first question was if it&amp;rsquo;s secure, the second question was how secure is it. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;: Well now that wasn&amp;rsquo;t even a question at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-is-no-such-thing-as-perfect-security&#34;&gt;There is no such thing as perfect security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most information security practitioners do a poor job explaining the relative nature of security.  Secure relative to what? A bot that looks for un-patched systems? A determined hacker? A nation-state?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is a &amp;ldquo;scale of difficulty&amp;rdquo; – like mountain climbing. Everest was thought to be unclimbable until Sir Edmund Hillary did it.  Everest was finally tackled by a massive expedition with enormous resources. The 1953 expedition totaled over 400 people, including 362 porters, 20 Sherpa guides and 10,000 lbs of baggage.  It was analogous to a military assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given enough time and resources &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; security can be defeated.  The main goal of security is to raise the time and resources required to an unreasonable level.  But how do you really know how secure something is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like mountain climbing, security can and should be rated/evaluated based on actual experience. Also like mountain climbing there are initial conditions that indicate a “tough climb” or an easy one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conditions-for-high-security-levels&#34;&gt;Conditions for high security levels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The technology is widely deployed/adopted.&lt;/strong&gt; Note that being widely deployed does NOT mean the technology is secure (Windows XP was widely deployed). It simply means that we are more likely to have lots of data about its security performance. The more opportunities and incentives for attack will give us more data, which increases our confidence of it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;rating&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The technology or system is attacked frequently with great intensity.&lt;/strong&gt; Ideally because of being widely deployed, it would be used is places that expose it to attack. Ideally those attacks are unrelenting.  This also increases our data about its security performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The technology is simple to install and configure.&lt;/strong&gt; Many supposedly &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo; systems are dependent on how they are installed, or post-install &amp;ldquo;hardening&amp;rdquo;.  Systems and technologies must be &amp;ldquo;secure by default&amp;rdquo; when installed and easily installed properly by non-specialists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open code base.&lt;/strong&gt; An open code base allows for infinitely many sets of eyes to review the code, and infinitely many developers to fix any vulnerabilities found.  Open code bases do &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; mean the code is secure.  However, there are generally fewer issues, and when issues are found they are addressed faster. They also tend to be widely deployed and tend to be less complex to install and maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug Bounty Program&lt;/strong&gt;. Public, open &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugcrowd.com/list-of-bug-bounty-programs&#34;&gt;Bug Bounty Programs&lt;/a&gt; encourage vulnerability research in a responsible manner. As an economist by training I believe when the rewards for good behavior are there you tend to get good behavior. If not, only bad behavior is rewarded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conditions-for-low-security-levels&#34;&gt;Conditions for low security levels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not widely deployed&lt;/strong&gt; The less widely the technology is deployed and used the fewer opportunities we have to gather good data about it’s security profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not frequently attacked, or successful attacks are generally not disclosed.&lt;/strong&gt; This goes hand in glove with the above point. One issue with vendor sofware used in specialized applications within companies is that successful attacks may not be recognized/known, and/or they may not be disclosed. This gives us low information quality about the actual security performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficult to install and configure properly.&lt;/strong&gt; ERP applications such as SAP are notoriously complex and difficult to install. The database has over 70,000 tables excluding Y and Z tables, the overall system takes days to setup by highly trained specialists. The attack surface is quite large. SAP may not be a good example because security is good by default and we rarely hear about successful breaches - but the risk in the complexity is real.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closed code base&lt;/strong&gt; If you have to ask your vendor “is it secure?” then it’s not.  Security isn&amp;rsquo;t something you can provide an answer to unless you&amp;rsquo;re selling snake oil. If the vendor says: “It&amp;rsquo;s secure. We did not put in any back doors. We audited the code ourselves. There are not any kernel level hacks, root kits, or otherwise. This has been tested against a variety of anti-virus scanners and none of them flagged anything. We&amp;rsquo;re very good. Please, please trust us.” then you should know that they are telling you what you want, or need to hear. You could read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb457059.aspx&#34;&gt;WinXP pamphlet&lt;/a&gt; on security back when it was released and it had endless bullet points about how secure it was. It was probably the least secure software in the history of computing based on actual attacks after the fact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-s-secure-until-it-s-not&#34;&gt;It’s secure… until it’s not&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1770s Joseph Bramah created a lock that was vastly superior to any the world ever seen. Bramah believed it was 100% theft-proof. Bramah was so confident in his design that he published a pamphlet detailing exactly how it worked and he put it in the window of his London storefront, and painted on it a challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The artist who can make an instrument that will pick or open this lock shall receive 200 Guineas the moment it is produced.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Jeremiah Chubb created the Chubb detector lock. The way Chubb’s lock worked was that if a lock picker tried to lift one of the tumblers up too high, a latching mechanism would trigger, causing the lock to seize up. When that happened, even the key wouldn’t open the lock. To reset the lock, the owner would have to put in a different key and rotate it in the opposite direction to reset the tumblers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, if lock owners went to unlock a chest, or a vault, or a front door, and found that their key didn’t work, they would know that someone had tried to get in—and that they had failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 70 years, the names Chubb and Bramah meant “perfect security”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1851, London was hosting The Great Exhibition—the first international exhibition of manufactured products. One of the attendees was A. C. Hobbs, an American locksmith. Back in the states, Hobbs had made a name for himself by showing bank managers that their locks could be easily picked, and convincing them to buy one of his. Hobbs was selling lots of locks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On day one of the exhibition, Hobbs publicly announced that he would pick the Chubb detector lock — the one that stops working if you pick it incorrectly. It took Hobbs about 25 minutes. And the way Hobbs did it was to use the lock against itself.
He would pick it until he tripped the detector mechanism, causing the lock to seize up. That would give Hobbs information about how it worked, and then he would pick the lock in the opposite direction to reset the detector. He’d go back and forth firing and resetting the detector until the lock told him everything he needed to know about how to get it open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Chubb detector lock was really just a warm up. The main event was the Bramah safety lock—the one with the challenge painted on it in gold lettering, which had been sitting Bramah’s storefront window for 70 years, unbeaten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working on the lock for about 52 hours over the course of fourteen days, Hobbs opened it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overnight, the feeling of perfect security had evaporated. And we have never gotten it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/in-1851-a-man-picked-two-unpickable-locks-and-changed-1698557792&#34;&gt;In 1851 a man picked two unpickable locks&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Automate Code Reviews?</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2015/09/06/why-automate-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2015/09/06/why-automate-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask a programmer to review 10 lines of code, they&amp;rsquo;ll make 10 suggestions. Ask them to review 1,000 lines of code and they&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;it looks good!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people have begun integrating bots into the GitHub ecosystem for code review. For example the folks who created the Bootstrap UI framework created a bot called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github/twbs/rorshach&#34;&gt;rorshach&lt;/a&gt; to perform sanity checks on pull requests. If the sanity check fails it leaves a nice informative comment, explaining the issue and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another example at &lt;a href=&#34;https://betterdiff.com/&#34;&gt;BetterDiff&lt;/a&gt;. The idea there is that instead of having humans go through and give cursory reviews, you have a round of automated review by bots (using normal, industry-standard tooling) and it comments on the pull request just like a reviewer would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty soon I expect to see &amp;ldquo;when tests pass, and code reviews pass, then go ahead and merge the code&amp;rdquo; bots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FinTech Startups Tug the Industry Forward</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2015/06/15/fintech-startups-tug-the-industry-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2015/06/15/fintech-startups-tug-the-industry-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/billguard.png&#34; alt=&#34;FinTech&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial services companies are among the most highly regulated industries in the world.  They also suffer from a trust issue.  Trust is a key ingredient in making a financial services business viable. Why would I ever buy insurance, banking services or invest my savings via a company that I didn’t trust?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sub-prime debt crisis in 2008 it became clear that the financial services industry would need to rebuild it’s image. Companies would need to zealously rebuild their brands to aspire to become “trusted advisors”. From an IT standpoint it is crystal clear that client and corporate data must be guarded and protected to prevent any loss as well as minimize the potential for damage to an organization’s reputation. How to manage the risk and yet stay innovative?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The response by some financial services companies is to stick their head in the sand and avoid &amp;ldquo;the cloud&amp;rdquo;, open source technologies, and try to make their networks ever more restrictive. This backfires in several ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their economics are always working against them relative to more open competitors, which they justify by convincing themselves that they are more secure and it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;worth it&amp;rdquo;. However managed properly their competitors are just as secure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their employees skills go stale. Since IT personnel cost so much the result is  mismanging a key resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By outsourcing aspects of their security to companies like Oracle, Microsoft and IBM they convince themselves they are more secure.  Does anyone know how many vulnerabilities there have been in the .NET framework &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cvedetails.com/vulnerability-list/vendor_id-26/product_id-2002/Microsoft-.net-Framework.html&#34;&gt;over the years&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employees will begin actively circumventing security when it impedes their ability to do their job. I&amp;rsquo;ve met employees who use their personal laptops on open Wi-Fi because they tell me they can&amp;rsquo;t work on their corporate laptop and network because it is so locked down.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s even worse than the problems listed above is the &lt;strong&gt;market never stands still&lt;/strong&gt;.  Your future competitors are today&amp;rsquo;s startups. FinTech companies are improving payment processes, reducing fraud, saving users money, promoting financial planning and responsibility, improving lending, and ultimately moving a giant, cautious industry forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we look at a recent article in Forbes that profiles &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/ilyapozin/2014/12/14/15-fintech-startups-to-watch-in-2015/&#34;&gt;15 FinTech startups to watch in 2015&lt;/a&gt; we can then also peek at the technologies they are using as see where the future lies with financial services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.billguard.com/&#34;&gt;BillGuard&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Apache, postmark, ZenDesk, Amazon AWS, Cloudflare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://planwise.com/&#34;&gt;PlanWise&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Apache, MailChimp, Wordpress, PHP, Fastly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ondeck.com/home-qualify/&#34;&gt;OnDeck&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Azure, Wordpress, PHP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wealthfront.com/&#34;&gt;WealthFront&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Amazon AWS, Cloudfront&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.currencycloud.com/&#34;&gt;CurrencyCloud&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Varnish, Mandrill, Cloudflare, Google Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stripe.com/&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Amazon AWS, Mandrill, Ruby on Rails, Google Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epiphyte.com/&#34;&gt;Epiphyte&lt;/a&gt;: Office 365, Azure, Node.js/Express, Bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.astropaycard.com/&#34;&gt;AstroPay&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Amazon AWS, PHP, AngularJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bankingup.com/&#34;&gt;BankingUp&lt;/a&gt;: Apache, Google Apps,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://squareup.com/&#34;&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Ruby on Rails, Amazon Cloudfront CDN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tipalti.com/&#34;&gt;Tipalti&lt;/a&gt;: IIS, nginx, Google Apps, Rackspace, Wordpress, PHP, .NET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flint.com/&#34;&gt;Flint&lt;/a&gt;: Apache, Amazon AWS, Google Apps, PHP, Akamai CDN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check - Acquired by Intuit (no info available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zipmark.com/&#34;&gt;Zipmark&lt;/a&gt;: Cowboy(erlang), Postmark, Google Apps, Amazon AWS, Ruby on Rails, Heroku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wepay.com/&#34;&gt;WePay&lt;/a&gt;: nginx, Amazon AWS, Mailgun, Zendesk, Google Apps, Akamai CDN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can we take away from this list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fintech startups are not afraid of open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fintech startups are taking advantange of cloud economics and scale (AWS, Rackspace and Azure as examples).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fintech startups are not afraid of using other &amp;ldquo;startup&amp;rdquo; services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet they also must be solving the security issue as well - what the most tenuous point in any companies lifespan and the one where trust matters the most?  The startup phase.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will this mean for incumbent companies that refuse to change? Maybe in the future they will be both secure and irrelevant.  Or worse, maybe just irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Technology data from &lt;a href=&#34;http://builtwith.com/&#34;&gt;builtwith.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;New&#39; New Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2015/05/25/the-new-new-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2015/05/25/the-new-new-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/satya-nadella-microsoft-ceo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Microsoft&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of Microsoft during my whole technical career.  However I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend Microsoft any longer for server workloads, and haven&amp;rsquo;t for years due to the fact that the Linux ecosystem is far less expensive and has more innovative people working on it and sharing what they do openly. However, I am very impressed with the direction and leadership of Satya Nadella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows-package-manager&#34;&gt;Windows Package Manager&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Windows 10 we are launching a new Package Management feature (formerly referred to as OneGet) that enables ITPros or DevOps to automate software discovery, installation, and inventory (SDII), locally or remotely, no matter what the installer technology is and where the software is located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why are we implementing Package Management? In the Linux world, people are familiar with package managers such as Apt-Get, YUM, RPM, etc, for different Linux distros.  In the Windows world, however, there are quite a few installer technologies, each having their own way to install software, such as MSI, MSU, APPX, and the list goes on and on. This creates a challenge for ITPros and DevOps and a need for a tool to automate the software deployment experience.  PackageManagement is aimed at solving this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;net-for-linux-and-mac&#34;&gt;.NET for Linux and Mac&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.NET Core supports Windows, OS X and Linux. You can write Universal apps on Windows 10 and ASP.NET 5 and Console apps on all of the three OSes. FreeBSD support is in progress, led by the .NET open source community. We expect that the community will create other OS ports. In fact, the OS X port has also been community led.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.NET Core supports x86, x64 and ARM CPUs in order to support device, cloud and console app scenarios. We expect that to see more chips come online, particularly given the LLILC LLVM integration project. LLILC will (in theory) make it possible to port .NET Core to all of the chips that LLVM supports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The .NET Core is open source on GitHub!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-studio-code&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This marks the first time that Microsoft offers developers a true cross-platform code editor. The full Visual Studio is still Windows-only, but today’s announcement shows the company’s commitment to supporting other platforms.  What is really fascinating is they built it with SAME basic architecture as GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Atom editor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Architecturally, Visual Studio Code combines the best of web, native, and language-specific technologies. Using the &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Electron Shell, Code combines web technologies such as JavaScript and Node.js with the speed and flexibility of native apps&lt;/strong&gt;. Code uses a newer, faster version of the same industrial-strength HTML-based editor that has powered the “Monaco” cloud editor, Internet Explorer&amp;rsquo;s F12 Tools, and other projects. And Code uses a tools service architecture that enables it to use many of the same technologies that power Visual Studio, including Roslyn for .NET, TypeScript, the Visual Studio debugging engine, and more. In future previews, as we continue to evolve and refine this architecture, Visual Studio Code will include a public extensibility model that lets developers build and use plug-ins, and richly customize their edit-build-debug experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all incredible coming from Microsoft.  Way to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2015/04/29/microsoft-shocks-the-world-with-visual-studio-code-a-free-code-editor-for-os-x-linux-and-windows/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Launches Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/Docs&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2015/04/29/microsoft-launches-its-net-distribution-for-linux-and-mac/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Launches Its .NET Distribution For Linux And Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.technet.com/b/packagemanagement/archive/2015/04/29/introducing-packagemanagement-in-windows-10.aspx&#34;&gt;Introducing PackageManagement in Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Big Bets</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2015/01/22/make-big-bets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2015/01/22/make-big-bets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/african_children.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Children&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation just released it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gatesnotes.com/2015-annual-letter?page=0&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;WT.mc_id=01_21_2015_AL2015-GF_GFO_domain_Top_21&#34;&gt;annual letter&lt;/a&gt;.  I have come to look forward to these letters because I find them incredibly inspiring. This year instead of an annual update they are re-baselining and taking a fifteen year view of the future. As I read this year&amp;rsquo;s letter I was simultaneously moved, inspired and awed by the scope their mission:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The lives of people in poor countries will improve faster in the next 15 years than &lt;strong&gt;at any other time in history&lt;/strong&gt;. And their lives will improve more than anyone else&amp;rsquo;s.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;mdash; 2015 Gates Annual Letter&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four pillars to accomplish this mission:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daughter and I spent 10 days traveling in Uganda several years ago with our friends Jeff Jensen and his daughter Caroline.  We traveled fairly extensively and visited a number of charitable organizations in and around Kampala and Gulu.  It&amp;rsquo;s hard to appreciate how far ahead we are economically unless you experience it first hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the places we visited was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.krochetkids.org/&#34;&gt;Krochet Kids&lt;/a&gt; in Gulu. They are the largest employer of women in the area. They provide job training, a fair wage to lift them and their families out of poverty, and a positive family-oriented environment. On a side note you can buy their products in Nordstrom!  This picture is &amp;ldquo;the factory&amp;rdquo; on the day we visited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/krochet-kids.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Children&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see the women get to sit in the shade of large trees, children are welcome, and they are encouraged to socialize as they work. The women I met were very happy and grateful for the opportunity.  However we found out that when the women got paid (cash - they do not have bank accounts) their husbands would take the money.  Some husbands would go drinking or find other ways to spend the money unwisely. The women were not empowered culturally to resist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founders of Krochet Kids decided they needed to find a way to create a type of bank where the women could protect their wages. If they didn&amp;rsquo;t bring home cash their husbands would not have access to it. The key was to find a way to allow them to save money in an account, and also possibly loan each other money.  The Village Savings and Loans Association (VSLA) was born. Currently on any given week there is roughly $10,000 being saved in the VSLA. The VSLA now offers small loans to women in the group and collects and divides any interest incurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Krochet Kids discovered was that in some ways the most valuable service they provided was not &amp;ldquo;a job&amp;rdquo; but rather training and mentorship on personal budgeting, savings, loans and business management topics.  One of their stated goals is now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To equip the women of Northern Uganda with the financial assets and knowledge to enter into the local economy and thereby end their dependence on humanitarian aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading this year&amp;rsquo;s Gates Letter Mobile Banking is one of the four pillars of the fifteen year plan. I have seen firsthand how empowering this can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gatesfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.krochetkids.org/&#34;&gt;Krochet Kids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://restoreinternational.org/&#34;&gt;Restore International&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bobgoff.com/&#34;&gt;Bob Goff&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep it Simple... UX Design</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2015/01/13/keep-it-simple...-ux-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2015/01/13/keep-it-simple...-ux-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/iron_man.png&#34; alt=&#34;Iron Man&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having done some user interface work over the break I discovered that my design approach was basically to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look around the web for things that I liked and then proceed to &amp;lsquo;borrow&amp;rsquo; their aesthetic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage UX/UI frameworks such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://foundation.zurb.com/&#34;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining a framework with something I think &amp;ldquo;looks cool&amp;rdquo; is a quick win.  I can get something created quickly that has an incredible amount of time and effort already baked in to making it usable, responsive and approachable.  Given the very wide of use of these frameworks I suspect many others work this way, but also since users are used to seeing many sites built with these frameworks it creates sense of familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am definitely not a designer and usually this is a cerebral as I get when it comes to UX/UI design work but I decide to step back and think about what we were trying accomplish. For example what are the base principles that could guide us?  I found some good material from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nngroup.com/&#34;&gt;Nielsen Norman Group&lt;/a&gt; that I want to share (I hope it&amp;rsquo;s OK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nielsen&amp;rsquo;s 10 Heuristic Design Principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;visibility-of-system-status&#34;&gt;VISIBILITY OF SYSTEM STATUS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system should always keep users informed about what is going on, through appropriate feedback within reasonable time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;match-between-system-and-the-real-world&#34;&gt;MATCH BETWEEN SYSTEM AND THE REAL WORLD&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system should speak the users&amp;rsquo; language, with words, phrases and concepts familiar to the user, rather than system-oriented terms. Follow real-world conventions, making information appear in a natural and logical order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;user-control-and-freedom&#34;&gt;USER CONTROL AND FREEDOM&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users often choose system functions by mistake and will need a clearly marked &amp;ldquo;emergency exit&amp;rdquo; to leave the unwanted state without having to go through an extended dialogue. Support undo and redo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;consistency-and-standards&#34;&gt;CONSISTENCY AND STANDARDS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users should not have to wonder whether different words, situations, or actions mean the same thing. Follow platform conventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;error-prevention&#34;&gt;ERROR PREVENTION&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even better than good error messages is a careful design which prevents a problem from occurring in the first place. Either eliminate error-prone conditions or check for them and present users with a confirmation option before they commit to the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;recognition-rather-than-recall&#34;&gt;RECOGNITION RATHER THAN RECALL&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimize the user&amp;rsquo;s memory load by making objects, actions, and options visible. The user should not have to remember information from one part of the dialogue to another. Instructions for use of the system should be visible or easily retrievable whenever appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;flexibility-and-efficiency-of-use&#34;&gt;FLEXIBILITY AND EFFICIENCY OF USE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accelerators &amp;ndash; unseen by the novice user &amp;ndash; may often speed up the interaction for the expert user such that the system can cater to both inexperienced and experienced users. Allow users to tailor frequent actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;aesthetic-and-minimalist-design&#34;&gt;AESTHETIC AND MINIMALIST DESIGN&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dialogues should not contain information which is irrelevant or rarely needed. Every extra unit of information in a dialogue competes with the relevant units of information and diminishes their relative visibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;help-users-recognize-diagnose-and-recover-from-errors&#34;&gt;HELP USERS RECOGNIZE, DIAGNOSE, AND RECOVER FROM ERRORS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Error messages should be expressed in plain language (no codes), precisely indicate the problem, and constructively suggest a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;help-and-documentation&#34;&gt;HELP AND DOCUMENTATION&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it is better if the system can be used without documentation, it may be necessary to provide help and documentation. Any such information should be easy to search, focused on the user&amp;rsquo;s task, list concrete steps to be carried out, and not be too large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main area that I struggle with is keeping it simple and minimal.  I tend to want to create &amp;ldquo;Tony Stark&amp;rdquo; approved interfaces, yet in the real world I strongly prefer clean simplicity. Check out this example from the retailer Victoria Beckham:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/VICTORIA_BECKHAM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Victoria Beckham&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product is front and center and draws your eye.  The navigation is minimal.  The buying options are as limited as possible, you can only choose your size.  Yet there is nothing missing - I can get more details if I want, or a size guide if needed.  To me, this is oustanding UI/UX.  It is clean, simple and usable, and it highlights the product and only the product. What is your ideal UI/UX?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nngroup.com/&#34;&gt;Nielsen Norman Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.victoriabeckham.com&#34;&gt;Victoria Beckham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://userium.com/&#34;&gt;Userium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Obama&#39;s Plan for a Free and Open Internet</title>
      <link>https://danstroot.com/2014/11/10/president-obamas-plan-for-a-free-and-open-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danstroot.com/2014/11/10/president-obamas-plan-for-a-free-and-open-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danstroot.com/img/obama_internet.png&#34; alt=&#34;Obama Internet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today President Barack Obama has come out in favor of net neutrality in very public way.  He lays out in no uncertain terms that he believes no cable company or access provider should be able to put limits on access to the Internet. In addition, he’s suggesting that the FCC recognizes access to the Internet as a basic utility, and something that Americans have a basic right to. This means no blocking, no throttling, more transparency and no paid prioritization.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the four principles quoted directly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No blocking.&lt;/strong&gt; If a consumer requests access to a website or service, and the content is legal, your ISP should not be permitted to block it. That way, every player — not just those commercially affiliated with an ISP — gets a fair shot at your business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No throttling.&lt;/strong&gt; Nor should ISPs be able to intentionally slow down some content or speed up others — through a process often called “throttling” — based on the type of service or your ISP’s preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased transparency.&lt;/strong&gt; The connection between consumers and ISPs — the so-called “last mile” — is not the only place some sites might get special treatment. So, I am also asking the FCC to make full use of the transparency authorities the court recently upheld, and if necessary to apply net neutrality rules to points of interconnection between the ISP and the rest of the Internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No paid prioritization.&lt;/strong&gt; Simply put: No service should be stuck in a “slow lane” because it does not pay a fee. That kind of gatekeeping would undermine the level playing field essential to the Internet’s growth. So, as I have before, I am asking for an explicit ban on paid prioritization and any other restriction that has a similar effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether you are on the &amp;ldquo;red team&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;blue team&amp;rdquo; - this is a noble goal and one I hope everyone supports. An open Internet benefits us all in a myriad of ways and allows a free and open exchange of ideas across society. I&amp;rsquo;d urge you to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raptitude.com/2014/11/the-gift/&#34;&gt;The Greatest Gift We Ever Had&lt;/a&gt;.  Key quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;honest, inclusive conversation across a society will reliably lead to equality and higher quality of life, in any place it is allowed to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-thoughts&#34;&gt;My Thoughts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one principle missing: &lt;strong&gt;No Content Modification.&lt;/strong&gt; ISPs should not be allowed to modify any of the content they transport.  This prevents them from injecting beacons, tracking code, advertising, etc. into web content that they are entrusted to deliver.  This is happening and it needs to be stopped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Government Regulation&amp;rdquo; is known to increase costs, and potentially reduce growth and innovation.  All things being equal I am in favor of less regulation rather than more regulation.  We need to tread carefully as we seek to increase regulation to protect openness (bit of an oxymoron isn&amp;rsquo;t it?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have to think carefully about the paid access issue. Does &amp;ldquo;no slow lanes&amp;rdquo; also mean &amp;ldquo;No Fast Lanes&amp;rdquo;?  What if I want an ISP to provide a service where I get premium access to YouTube content, or Netflix content?  Should that be illegal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not a requirement that ISPs block unlawful content, rather it is a prohibition on blocking lawful content. But a strong enough prohibition on blocking lawful content (e.g., one which provides consequences whenever lawful content is blocked, even if the intent was to block unlawful content and the lawful content just got caught up in the filter) actually reduces the incentive for ISPs to attempt to identify and block unlawful content, since attempting to do so but making a misidentification in the process can result in penalties.  In other words access to child pornography, terrorist information, and illicit drugs could actually increase as a result (i.e. &amp;ldquo;the law of unintended consequences&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-is-president-obama-s-video&#34;&gt;Here is President Obama&amp;rsquo;s Video:&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/uKcjQPVwfDk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who considers himself a Republican It saddens me that this issue has become so polarized along party lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Net Neutrality&amp;quot; is Obamacare for the Internet; the Internet should not operate at the speed of government.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Senator Ted Cruz (@SenTedCruz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SenTedCruz/status/531834493922189313&#34;&gt;November 10, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only similarity to the Affordable Care Act is that Obama supports it. There may be a rational, reasoned argument against Net Neutrality, but Republicans aren’t making it, and neither are the cable companies or cellular providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thrust seems to be &amp;ldquo;Government regulation of the Internet will be bad.&amp;rdquo;  And yet, we seem to have no issues regulating banks, power utilities, telephone companies and other utilities.  The other argument seems to be the &amp;ldquo;slippery slope&amp;rdquo; argument - by introducing goverment regulation it is easy to envision that we will soon start regulating &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;/strong&gt;.  However, with our country&amp;rsquo;s foundation on free speech I find that argument quite a stretch and exactly the opposite of Obama&amp;rsquo;s first principle: &amp;ldquo;No Blocking&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whitehouse.gov/net-neutrality&#34;&gt;White House - President Obama&amp;rsquo;s Plan for a Free and Open Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>